# **Matthew Dolan**

## iOS Software Engineer Vancouver, BC

778-322-8135 - mdolancode@gmail.com

LinkedIn https://www.linkedin.com/in/mdolancode

GitHub https://github.com/mdolancode

I am an **iOS Software Engineer with two years of experience** and have previously worked in the EV industry. Besides iOS Development, I have interests in crypto, and creating electronic music plus I'm formerly a world-class competitive bagpiper!

#### Skills

Languages: Swift, Objective-C

Design Patterns: Object-Oriented Programming, MVC, MVVM, Delegates, Coordinator

Frameworks: UIKit, SwiftUI, Realm, Alamofire, AVFoundation, Core Bluetooth, Core Data, Combine

Tools: Xcode, Git, GitHub, Cocoapods, Homebrew, Jira, Confluence, Jenkins

Other: Code Review, REST APIs, Agile Methodologies, Apple Human Interface Guidelines, App

Submission & Review Process

# **Experience**

## Indie iOS Developer - Matthew Dolan Apps

December 2020 - Present, Vancouver, BC

Detroit 909 https://apps.apple.com/us/app/detroit-909/id1560868575

Anime Quotes! https://github.com/mdolancode/Anime-Quotes

- Developed "Detroit-909" and "AnimeQuotes!" independently and used Object-Oriented Programming, Swift and UIKit.
- Submitted "Detroit-909" to the AppStore review process and successfully published the app with over 100+ downloads.
- Built a drum sampler using the AVFoundation framework and triggered samples.
- Implemented the MessageUI framework to launch a screen of the native email app so users can communicate with the developer.
- Created an anime guotes app, parsed the API data using Alamofire and displayed it in the table view.
- · Engineered the navigation using the coordinator pattern for the view controllers and future scalability.
- Programmed a VoiceOver accessibility feature, so the user can perform the Z gesture to dismiss the screen.
- Linked the app and connected it to the web by using the Safari Services framework.

#### Software Development Engineer, iOS - Rivian Automotive

December 2019 - December 2020, Vancouver BC

- Worked at a fast-paced EV startup with four other iOS Developers that grew to seven and built the app from the ground up with Object-Oriented Programming, Swift and UIKit to interface with electric vehicles.
- Engineered the app foundation using the coordinator pattern to manage view controller presentation to create scalability.
- Created UI flow for the login for confirmation and error handling, so users receive a notification for success or failure.
- Developed the app UI and created a good user experience.
- Partnered with the design team and iterated on UI elements and styling to meet brand guidelines.
- Delivered a proof of concept app using Native iOS (Swift and Objective-C) and React-Native to prove future integration was possible.

- · Received and contributed to code reviews to improve the codebase.
- Exposed to MVVM. Core Bluetooth. Core Data and Combine.
- Tested the Android and iOS app to improve the outgoing product.
- · Facilitated scrum meetings remotely and attained Alpha and Beta release versions.
- · Streamlined the sprint process and gave time back to developers.

## Frontend Developer - Mountain Town Dev

February 2018 - November 2019, Vancouver BC

- Developed static websites for local artists to help them gain a web presence and showcase their work.
- Built sites using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, ¡Query, and WordPress.

#### **Teacher Assistant - Vancouver School Board**

June 2013 - November 2019, Vancouver BC

- Worked collaboratively with administration, specialists, teachers, and other teaching assistants to help students with their education.
- Encouraged and helped students with special needs to reach their goals set out in their individual education plan.
- · Assisted students with learning technologies that include HTML, CSS, and Scratch.

#### Specialist / Technical Specialist - Apple Canada

August 2011 - November 2019, Vancouver BC

- Worked as part of the team in a fast-paced environment where ambiguity and change were the norms.
- Actively listened to customers' needs and provided personal, education, and small business solutions.
- Facilitated device setups and workshops for customers.
- · Troubleshoot customer devices and documented issues.
- · Mentored new hires, and provided feedback to help them grow.

#### **Education**

**CS50 - Intro to Computer Science** 

**HavardX** 

In-progress

iOS Developer Bootcamp

Udemy

August 2019

**Educational Assistant Certificate** 

Langara College

June 2013